(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-30T22:49:57.607242",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
君たち！100万人ありがとう！
You guys! Thank you for 1 million!
それじゃ今日は一日、テキトーにあのね、楽しんでってね！
So today, just take it easy and have fun, okay!
星空見上げ 私だけのヒカリ教えて
Look up at the starry sky, tell me my own light
あなたはいまどこで 誰といるのでしょうか?
Where are you now? And who are you with?
楽しくしてること思うと さみしくなって
When I think of you having fun, it makes me feel lonely
一緒に観たシネマひとりきりで流す
I play the movie we saw together all by myself
大好きなひとが遠い 遠すぎて泣きたくなるの
The person I love is far away, so far I want to cry
あした目が覚めたら ほら希望が生まれるかも Good night!
When I wake up tomorrow, hope just might be born. Good night!
I still I still I love you!
I'm waiting waiting forever
とまらないのよ Hi!!
I won't stop, hi!!
眠りのふちで ユメがくれる想い出の One day
At the edge of slumber, dreams bring memories of one day
あなたの言葉には 少しウソがあった
There was a little lie in your words
離さないよとキミだけだと 抱きしめたのに
Even though you held me close, saying you'd never let go
約束がフワリと暗い夜に消えた
The promise softly vanished into the dark night
大好きなひといつも いつまでも探ししてしまう
I'm forever and ever searching for the person I love
きっと目が覚めても まだ幻を感じたい morning
I'm sure even when I wake up, I still want to feel the illusion, morning
I lost I lost I lost you!
You're making making my music
もう逢えないの? No!
Can't we meet anymore? No!
大好きなひとが遠い 遠すぎて泣きたくなるの
The person I love is far away, so far I want to cry
あした目が覚めたら ほら希望が生まれるかも
When I wake up tomorrow, hope just might be born
魅惑を隠す箱 秘宝に香る危険な
A box hiding allure, the dangerous scent of treasure
dangerous marine smell ❤ ahoy ❤
dangerous marine smell ❤️ ahoy ❤️
「探してたのはせ・ん・ち・ょ・お?」ううん...
"What you were looking for is Cap-ta-in?" No...
「あん❤そんなにがっついちゃダメだぞ❤」
"Ah❤ Don't be so eager❤"
誘うガーネットの赤 極上の海賊の秘宝
The red of enticing garnet, the ultimate pirate's treasure,
艶が溢れ漂う 香りをどうか怖がらないで
overflowing with allure, please don't fear the scent,
開けてみて
and try opening it.
Sexy世界一 Superピチピチ ぶっちゃんけ船長捕まえたくない?
World's sexiest, super fresh. Don't you want to catch her?
私の甘さが 欲しいでしょ
Do you want my sweetness?
秘宝の鍵を優しく刺して 宝庫の扉マジで早く開けてね
Gently insert the key and open the vault door quickly!
はーい、もうなんですかね？
Hii, what is this?
調整に調整を重ねて、ついにこの
After adjustment after adjustment,
100万人記念ライブが来ましたよー！
finally this 1 million subscriber live is here!
なんと！3期生の みんなと ちょっと歌っていこうかなと思っていまして...
And what's more, I thought I'd sing a bit with everyone from Gen 3...
ちょっとね、どんな感じのライブなのかは...まあ見てのお楽しみということで...
So you'll just have to wait and see what kind of live it'll be...
ちょっと最後までね、色々とこだわって詰め込みましたので、セットとかね...
We've put a lot of attention and detail into the end, like the set and...
船長のやりたいを詰め込んでもらったライブとなってますので、ぜひ3期生の登場もお楽しみにしてください！
a live packed with what the captain wanted to do, so please look forward to the 3rd gen's appearance!
それじゃあまず、誰が来るのかな？あ、そうだ。
Well then, who's coming first? Ah, that's right.
ちょっと今日はね、ハッシュタグ #宝鐘マリン100万人記念 でいっぱい呟いてください！
Today, please tweet a lot with the hashtag #HoushouMarine1million!
スクショとかもね、してくださいね。可愛いところいっぱいお見せするので、スクショよろしく！
And take screenshots too. I'll show you lots of cute parts, so screenshots please!
ということで、じゃあ最初のゲストは誰かな？じゃあ早速次のステージへ、しゅっぱーつ！
So, who is the first guest? Well then, off to the next stage, set sail!
ギラギラ海のbeach way 夏のflow Again 願ってはやんちゃな一夜のgame ロックオン 君を待ってたんだ
Gleaming ocean beach way, summer flow again, wishing for a selfish one-night game. Lock on, I've been waiting for you,
ギラギラの一瞳で 口説くPlay途中も横切った ビキニ ガン見のscope ロックオン 一人だけロックオン
with gleaming eyes, flirting play, even cutting across halfway, scope of staring at bikinis. Lock on, lock on to just you.
苦渋の選択ああ神に逆らってでもこの刺激に満ちた季節を終わらせない
A bitter choice, ah, even rebelling against God, I won't let this season filled with excitement end.
夏が今僕の心広げてく 波風笑い声が Laka Laka love Laka Laka love
Summer is now opening up my heart, wave winds and laughter, Laka Laka love, Laka Laka love.
この空雲虹にのっかって 砂浜の君の足跡見つけ出すから 夏が今君と僕を引き寄せる 沈まない太陽が Laka Laka love Laka Laka love
Riding on this sky, cloud, and rainbow, I'll find your footprints on the sandy beach. Summer now draws you and me close, the unsetting sun, Laka Laka love, Laka Laka love.
海よ 春も冬も飲み干してゆけ まだまだ終わらせないこの夏は Laka Laka love Laka Laka love
O ocean, drink down spring and winter too, this summer won't end yet, Laka Laka love, Laka Laka love.
この空雲虹にのっかって 砂浜の君の足跡見つけ出すから
Riding on this sky, cloud, and rainbow, I'll find your footprints on the sandy beach.
行こうか 夜の同志達を 謀だらけの漂った関係
Shall we go, comrades of the night, in a relationship full of deceit?
夏が今僕の心広げてく 波風笑い声が Laka Laka love Laka Laka love
Summer is now opening up my heart, wave winds and laughter, Laka Laka love, Laka Laka love.
この空雲虹にのっかって 高山見下ろして 耳澄ましたら
Riding on this sky, cloud, and rainbow, looking down from high mountains, if I listen closely.
ロンリー ロンリー ロンリー ロンリーでいらぎら出てきたけど 心の中は...
Lonely, lonely, lonely, came out gleaming, but inside my heart...
ちょっと病気なセブンティーン
A somewhat sickly sort at seventeen,
枯れたインクとペンで絵を描いて
drawing pictures with dried-up ink and a pen.
継いで接いでまたマザーグース
Stitch and sew it like a mother goose,
夜は何回も泣いてまた明日
I'll cry through the night until tomorrow.
回る発条のアンダロイド
Just an android with a revolving mainspring—
僕の声と頭はがらんどう
my voice and head are both hollow.
光の色が広がっていく
With a light so bright that it spreads,
波風笑い声ががらからから
the sea breeze howls like laughter.
からからからこの空雲の間に乗っかって
From that radio tower in the distance,
砂浜の君の足あと見つけてから
we trace the path across the sky.
夏が今君と僕を引き寄せる沈まない太陽が
Summer has finally arrived...
からからからからからからからから春も秋も冬も
spring, autumn, and winter go by.
波打ってゆけまだまだ顔は終わらせないこの夏はからからからからからからからから
The waves keep crashing on, and we're not done yet—this is our summer.
ノエル！ / マリン！ / ありがとう！
Noel! / Marine! / Thank you!
すごかった！
That was amazing!
というわけで最初の曲はノエル時代が来ました！
So, that was our first song, "Noel-san's Era"!
はい！マリンありがとうございます！
Yay! Marine-san, thank you!
はい、ノエルとはねー、まぁお揃いのねこのサングラスもね、しちゃったりして。おしゃれでしょ。
Yay, Noel-san! We even wore matching sunglasses, super stylish, right?
いやもうね、このセンチュはね、このノエルのなんとかなんて言ったらいいんだろう。この前衛的なラップにね、
Well, this stage features Noel's... this avant-garde rap!
前衛的なラップ？
Avant-garde rap?
いや、なんか最初はね聴くたびにね、笑ってしまってね、膝からこう崩れ落ち続けて。膝から崩れ落ちてたんだけど。
At first, every time I heard it, I couldn't stop laughing. I kept collapsing at the knees!
さすがに何回もね聴いたからちょっとだいぶねもうね耐性がついたというか。
Naturally, after hearing it so many times...
いや寒いなってね。いえーい！いえーい！ちょっとヒヤッとした感じが出てたかなと。
Yeah, it's chilly, huh? Yeah! Yeah! I got a bit of a chill from it, I guess.
思います。どうだった、ノエルちゃん一緒に歌って。
How was it, Noel-chan? Did you enjoy singing it?
なんかやっぱさ、1人で歌うのと全然違うなと思って。ねえ！てかマリンなんかすげえかっこよかったなと。
Well, you know, singing alone is completely different. And Marine, you looked so cool!
本当？ / うん、すごい！
Really? / Yeah, amazing!
いやこの曲絶対1人だったらしんどいけど、なんかノエルちゃんにきついところ全部ね投げちゃった。
If anyone sang this alone, it'd be so tough, but Noel-chan, you took all the hard parts—
サビの高いところ全部ノエルちゃんに。楽しかったね！楽しかった！
all the high notes went to Noel-chan! It was so fun! It was a blast!
いやー、ノエル、まだまだね、この後もね続いていくわけですけども。お、続くのか。
Well, Noel, we still have more to come after this, / Oh, it continues?
次ね、誰だと思う？えー、でもどうだろうな。え、ラミィよ？
Who do you think is next? / Let's see... Lamy?
まあ、ラミィちゃんももちろん来るけど。ええ、じゃあポルカってよかな。
Well, Lamy would definitely come, of course. / Eh, then Polka?
ポルカちゃんももちろん来るけどね、次のはね。うん。フレイタが来るんだ？
That Polka would too, but next is... / Flare-tan is coming!
あー、フレイアか。まあ、そうだね。だんちょうお姉さん組で歌うの？
Ah, Flare. Well, that's right. Danchou, are you singing in a sisters unit?
ちょっとお礼しなきゃ、ちょっと。ノエル時代は終わったんだよ！終わったんだよ！
Wait, I should thank you first. Noel-en's era is over! It's finished!
これからはマリフレの時代です！え、なんでお礼する必要あるの？
From now on, it's the Marine-Furea era! Wait, why do you need to thank me?
お礼、いや、まあ、別に、何、お詫び事例みたいな感じで。じゃあ、だんちょうもっと可愛くしてあげる。
Well, you know, as a courtesy. Then Danchou will make you even cuter!
え、なに？可愛くしてあげるの。これがもっと可愛くなったら、いよいよ、これ以上可愛くなったら、いよいよ、あ、え？
What? If you get cuter, then finally—if you get any cuter than this...
なんかさ、マリンさんこの前ちょっと痩せたいみたいなこと言ってたよね？
You know, Marine, you said earlier that you wanted to lose weight, right?
言ってたからだんちょうがちょっとお肉柔らかくしてあげる。
So Danchou will make your meat softer!
じゃあ、ちょっとだんちょう。あ、でもこのあとフレアだよね？
Well then, Danchou... Oh, but the next song is Flare's, right?
フレア頑張ってね！だんちょう応援してるからね！
Flare, do your best! Danchou is cheering for you!
ギャラクシー☆ばばんがBang！
Galaxy ☆ Babanga Bang!
不知火フレア×宝鐘マリン
Shiranui Flare & Houshou Marine
もしも恋人が宇宙人なら
If my lover were an alien,
どんなデートになるのかな？
what kind of date would we have?
水星でちょっと水遊びして
Playing with water on Mercury for a bit,
土星の輪っかでひと滑り
sliding down Saturn's rings.
言葉なんていらないね
We don't need any words,
きっと楽しくて時間を忘れるでしょう
I'm sure we'll have so much fun we'll lose track of time.
金星で会えるきれいなヴィーナス
A beautiful Venus we can meet on Venus,
素敵なところへ連れてって
take me somewhere wonderful.
もしも恋人が宇宙人なら
If my lover were an alien,
パパもママもねぇ驚くわ
even mom and dad would be surprised.
木星でボイジャー待ち伏せしたら
If we wait to ambush Voyager on Jupiter,
火星で友達見つけるの
we'll find friends on Mars.
夢はいつか叶うもの
Dreams are things that come true one day,
心あわせて
matching our hearts
ワープできるね
we can warp, right?
地球は青くて綺麗だったと
That Earth was so blue and beautiful,
みんなに話してあげたいな
I want to tell everyone about it.
飛べよ発射オーライ砲
Fly away, launch all-right cannon!
天下御免のパスポート
A passport of absolute freedom,
ドラマティックに生きていくのに
living a dramatic life,
ダイブしようぜ
let's dive in!
大冒険！
A grand adventure!
感しゃ感激
Overwhelmed with gratitude,
月中ひらめいちゃって
a flash of inspiration mid-moon,
目と目が合えば
if our eyes meet,
またパタパタ天使がやってくる
fluttering angels come along again.
ドンマイ！どんまい！
Don't mind! Don't mind!
ほら吹いても
Even if you blow,
ピピ口笛吹いて
blow a pip-pip whistle,
すやすや眠れば
sleep soundly and peacefully,
明日は今日より未来です
tomorrow is a future beyond today.
歌手招待
Singer invitation!
お土産はアカデミア
Souvenirs are academia,
忘れちゃダメよ
don't forget them!
握手をしたら
Once we shake hands,
また会う日までごきげんよう
farewell until we meet again.
ため息なんてバイバイブー
Sighs are bye-bye boo!
鳴り響けチャンピオン
Ring out, champion!
いつも心に金メダル
Always a gold medal in our hearts.
シュプレヒコール右手を上げて
Raise your right hand in slogans,
バンバン！アレもこれも頼もう
bang bang! Let's order this and that too.
どこかにあるよパラダイス
Paradise is somewhere out there,
ニュースは秘密何が起こるかお楽しみ
the news is a secret, what will happen is a surprise.
ジ・エンド！ドキドキババンガバーン！
The end! Dokidoki babangabaan!
ジー・イー・エイチ！あとふた山アンバカーン！
G-E-H! Two more mountains ambakaan!
お土産はアカデミア
Souvenirs are academia,
忘れちゃダメよ
don't forget them!
握手をしたら
Once we shake hands,
また会う日までごきげんよう
farewell until we meet again.
ため息なんてバイバイブー
Sighs are bye-bye boo!
最初はグーでジャンケンポン！
Rock, paper, scissors, shoot with rock!
ドキドキコスター
Dokidoki coaster,
愛と勇気と夢ハリセン
love, courage, and a dream paper fan.
ハートのタボスピード上げて
Raise the turbo speed of the heart,
バンバン！飛べよ発射オーライ砲
bang bang! Fly away, launch all-right cannon!
天下御免のパスポート
A passport of absolute freedom,
ドラマティックに生きていくに
living a dramatic life,
ダイブしようぜ
let's dive in!
大冒険！
A grand adventure!
ねぇ、最後の曲何？
Hey, what was that last song?
え？ なんか…
Eh? Something like...
こうじゃんみたいな
Like this...
聞いてない？
You weren't listening?
え、なんか雰囲気でポーズ取るのかなって
Eh, I figured we'd just strike a pose with the mood.
これも何？
What about this too?
え？ G・E・H・ドキドキババンガバーン！
Eh? G-E-H! Dokidoki babangabaan!
最初によった…
First you got drunk...
違う違う、酔ってないよ！
No no, I'm not drunk!
酔っ払いにしていこっか、ってことで。
"Let's act like drunk people," is what we decided.
え、フレアとね、一緒に歌わせてもらいました。「恋人が宇宙人なら」！
Um, Flare and I got to sing "If My Lover Were an Alien" together!
ありがとう、呼んでくれて！
Thanks for inviting me!
でね、フレアとね、歌いたかったのこの曲はね。
And you know, I really wanted to sing this song with Flare.
うん。えっと、ギャラクシー・ババンガ・バーンって入っております、これね。はい。
Yeah. Um, it has "Galaxy Babanga Bahn" in it, this one. Yeah.
そうね、フレアとね、相談して決めた。結構他の曲はね、
That's right, Flare and I discussed and decided. Quite a few of the other songs...
割と船長の独断気味なんだけど（笑）
Are somewhat Captain's arbitrary choice, haha.
この曲はね、この曲で今日はフレアだからね。
This song, for this song today it's because it's Flare.
そうだね、提案があって、決めましたね。
That's right, you made a proposal and we decided on it.
フレアはなんでこれにしようと思ったの？
Flare, why did you decide to make it this one?
これさ、あの、私が提案したの、もう一個のあったんだけど、これと同じ感じで、あー、そう、一緒にだからね、あ、もう決まったんだよね。
This, um, I proposed another one, but it was similar to this, oh right, because we were together, oh, it was already decided.
ギャラクシーババンバンのほうだったっけ？そうそうそう、それでね、こっちにしましたと、いうことで。
Was it Galaxy Babamban? Yeah yeah yeah, so we went with this one, that's why.
ヒーリングがあったね。
It had a healing vibe.
懐かしい感じになったのかなって。
I wondered if it gave a nostalgic feeling.
懐かしアニメソング、うちらは懐かしアニメソングを歌うから。
Nostalgia anime songs, since we sing nostalgic anime songs.
そうなんだよね、なんかマリンと一緒に歌うったら、やっぱりなんかそういうちょっとナツメロ、アニソンみたいなの、ね？もう結構シナジーあるなって思ってたから。
That's right, I thought if I sang with Marine, it would have some kind of nostalgic anime song synergy, you know?
せっかくならね、そういうの歌いたいなって。歌っちゃいました、楽しかったね！
If we have the chance, we wanted to sing something like that. We sang it, it was fun!
楽しかったね！
It was fun!
これからもね、まだナツメロアニソンをね、大体歌うと思って、いるんですけども。
We still plan to sing nostalgic anime songs from time to time, though.
いや、でもね、さっきノエルちゃんがね、プュルプュル怒ってたけど。
Well, but you know, earlier Noeru-chan was getting all puru-puru angry.
うん、最後ね、なんかノエルちゃんから...
Yeah, at the end, like from Noel-chan...
なんか呼ばれたような
Feels like I got called...
いやでもどう、フレア楽しかったでしょ？
Well anyway, Flare, wasn't it fun?
楽しかったよ！
It was fun!
楽しいね！
So much fun!
ではこのまま二人でライブする？
So, shall the two of us do a live right now?
うんなんないたほうがいいか、大丈
Wait, maybe not, is it okay...
すまんね、ノエルは（笑）
Sorry, Noel (laughs)
なんだ？
What?
一緒に踊って！頑張れ！
Dance with me! Do your best!
一緒に踊ってよ！一緒に、ん
Dance together with me! Together, um...
むっちゃ周り虫に決まってんだろ
Everyone's bound to be into bugs, right?
じゃ、ちょっとこれからね、じゃあノエルちゃんがすねてるかもしれないから一緒に
Well then, Noel might be sulking, so together...
ノエルちゃんに会いに行こっか
Let's go meet Noel-chan.
よっしゃ、行くか！
Alright, let's go!
じゃあ手繋いでいこっか
Then let's go holding hands.
が、これもちがう、これもちがう、ガタ、ノエル、がー
Wait, this is different too, shaking...
NEXT STAGE IS...
魅惑を隠す箱 秘宝に香る危うげな
A box hiding allure, emitting a dangerous scent of treasure,
dangerous marine smell
❤Ahoy❤
(これ開けたら君たちになんて言ってあげてべきかな…？)
(What should I say to you guys when I open this...?)
誘うガーネットの赤 極上の海賊の秘宝 それは私
The alluring garnet red, the ultimate pirate's treasure, that is me.
艶が溢れ漂う 香りをどうかしりごみしないで 開けてみて
Overflowing with allure, don't hesitate at the scent, try opening it.
(あ哈哈哈…❤)
(Ahahaha...❤)
PARTY NIGHT お姉さん組
PARTY NIGHT - Older Sister Group
いやなこと全部 忘れちゃおう
Let's forget about all the unpleasant things.
一晩眠って 目覚めたら Happy girl
Sleep for a night, and when you wake up, be a happy girl.
夢の途中で 出会う不思議
Encountering mysteries in the middle of a dream.
悪夢を食べてる バグたちも Good friend
Bugs eating nightmares are also good friends.
いつもならば おしゃべりもしない
Normally, we wouldn't even chat.
窮屈な人 大きな 螺旋で 変身～っ！
A stifling person, transforming in a huge spiral—!
Ahoy baby ウキウキLady ストレスは溜めないで
Ahoy baby, upbeat Lady, don't let stress build up.
Touch me baby キラキラBody リフレッシュしよう
Touch me baby, sparkling Body, let's refresh.
Ahoy baby 踊ろうSunday 心にも栄養を
Ahoy baby, let's dance Sunday, nourish your heart too.
Touch me baby 気分はHoliday 星空のメロディ
Touch me baby, feeling is Holiday, melody of the starry sky.
疲れすぎて 臆病な日には
On days when you're too tired and timid,
瞼とじて アクセスしてみて How about Party Night?
Close your eyelids and try accessing... How about Party Night?
Ahoy baby ウキウキLady ストレスは溜めないで
Ahoy baby, upbeat Lady, don't let stress build up.
Touch me baby キラキラBody リフレッシュしよう
Touch me baby, sparkling Body, let's refresh.
Ahoy baby 踊ろうSunday 心にも栄養を
Ahoy baby, let's dance Sunday, nourish your heart too.
Touch me baby 気分はHoliday 星空のメロディ
Touch me baby, feeling is Holiday, melody of the starry sky.
Ahoy baby ウキウキLady ストレスは溜めないで Touch me baby キラキラBody リフレッシュしよう
Ahoy baby, upbeat Lady, don't let stress build up, Touch me baby, sparkling Body, let's refresh.
Ahoy baby 踊ろうSunday キラキラBody リフレッシュしよう
Ahoy baby, let's dance Sunday, sparkling Body, let's refresh.
いや楽しかったね！
Man, that was so fun!
懐かしいね！
So nostalgic!
懐かしいよね。さっきのフレアからの引き続いての、懐かしアニメソングでお送りしました。
Very nostalgic. We brought you that nostalgic anime song continuing from Flare's earlier.
デジキャラットだったね。パーティタイムも歌いました。
It was Di Gi Charat. We also sang Party Time.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
パーティナイトな？あれ？パーティナイト…パーティナイトか！
Party Night? Huh? Party Night... Party Night!
船長間違えました。
Captain made a mistake.
これはね、えっとフレアとね元々最初候補にあって、で、ていうか三人曲だし
Originally this was a candidate with Flare, and well, since it's a three-person song...
お姉さん組の曲だしってなって、ちょっとノエルにプチコパート…
It's a song for the older sister group, so Noel got a Petit Charat part...
私のこと好きすぎか？
Do you love me too much?
ギュッて、怖い怖い怖い！
Hug... scary scary scary!
いやでも、なんかノエルちゃんはてっきりまだ怒ってんのかなって思ったけど怒ってなくてよかった。怒ってるよ？
But you know, I thought Noel-chan might still be mad, but I'm glad she's not. I am mad, you know?
怒ってんの？
Are you mad?
なんでも、でも、三期生フレアがいるからね、機嫌は…
But still, since Flare is in the 3rd generation, her mood is...
誤解だからねノエルちゃん言うの。誤解？あ、本当？誤解？
Noel-chan, that's a misunderstanding. Misunderstanding? Oh really? Misunderstanding?
そう、あれ、やりさせる、
Yeah, let's have them do it...
そうね。触れ合いな…
That's right. Such intimacy...
本当にお前を思ってくれる女っての…見落としてるよだな。
A woman who truly cares about you... you're overlooking her.
触れ合い良いのかな、そんなんで…
Is that kind of intimacy okay...
ねぇ、この後いっぱいに素敵な時間を過ごそうか。
Hey, shall we spend a wonderful time together after this?
ご飯でも食べるかな。うんうんうん。
Shall we eat something? Yeah, yeah, yeah.
んで、てかさ、てかさ、待って待って、てかさ、これからはね…
And, I mean, wait, wait, from now on...
ちょっとみんな帰るのはまだ早いから。まだまだ早いから、そうそう、確かに。
It's still too early for everyone to go home. Still too early, exactly.
この後まだまだね、3期生全員集合なんだから。もちろん！
After this, all 3rd gen members are gathering together. Of course!
ペコもね、るっしゅもね、黒猫にかけるんでしょ？そう、確かに。
Peko too, Rushia too, dressing up as black cats, right? Exactly.
だからちょっとね、みんなスローだからね、まだまだ待ってもらって…
So everyone's going slow, please wait a bit longer...
ね、これからはね、ペコらとかと…これから歌おうと思いますので。うん。
And from now on, with Pekora and others... we'll be singing. Yeah.
じゃあちょっと、何ですか後半なのかな、これ。どの辺なのかなかんないけど。
Well then, what is this, the second half? Not sure which part it is.
後半気分に…うんうんうん、足を踏み込…
Getting into the second half mood... stepping into...
足を踏み込もうぜ！行ってこうぜ！
Let's step into it! Let's go!
NEXT STAGE IS...
嗚呼、素晴らしきニャン生
Ah, what a wonderful cat life
これは可愛いお嬢さん
Oh, what do we have here, a cute lady
真っ白な毛がとても素敵ね
Your white fur is so very lovely
こんな月が綺麗な夜は　僕と一緒に遊びませんか
In this night with a beautiful moon out, will you go out and play with me?
ニャン生は一度きり
A cat's life only comes once
楽しむが勝ちなのです
So let's live it to the fullest
あなたを縛る首輪は　噛み千切ってあげましょう
Let me chew up and tear the collar that binds you
野良は最高ニャンニャンニャン
Strays are the best, nyan nyan nyan
魚くすねて、ハト追いかけて
We can take fishes, and chase after pigeons
昼間は働く人間を　尻目に屋根の上で夢うつつ
We can just lie half-asleep on the roof watching human workers
あなたも自由にニャンニャンニャン
You can also live freely nyan nyan nyan
素敵な仲間も紹介しましょう
I'll introduce you to a lot of my cool pals
さあ、その窓を開けて　飛び出すのです!
Come on, just open the window right now, jump out and escape!
これは気まぐれな野良猫さん
Well, well, well, if it isn't that stray cat
闇の中目だけが光っている
Only your eyes shine through the darkness
随分口が上手いけれど
You have the sweetest words, but
私はバカな女じゃないわ
I am not a foolish girl like you think
ニャン生は一度きりだからこそ飼われるのよ
A cat's life comes just once, that's why I'm kept here
ブランド首輪の価値が　あなたには分かるかしら?
I wonder if you know the value of this branded collar?
私は優雅よニャンニャンニャン
I am a cat of class, nyan nyan nyan
美味しい食事にふかふかベッド
With delicious food and a soft bed
水はちょっぴり苦手だけど
I might be weak when it comes to water, but
毎日シャワーだって浴びれるの　それに比べてニャンニャンニャン
I take a shower every day too, compared to that, nyan nyan nyan
あなたは誰に守ってもらうの?
Who do you have to protect you?
明日車に轢かれるかも知れないじゃない!
Tomorrow you might get run over by a car, you never know!
そんな強気なところも素敵です
Even your stubbornness is so adorable
一層あなたを好きになりました
I think I've fallen in love with you more than ever
あら正直ね、でもそんなやり方じゃ
What frankness, but with that kind of method
ココロ揺らがないわ
You cannot sway this heart of mine
僕の夢はニャンニャンニャン
My dream is nyan nyan nyan
いつかはこの街を飛び出して
To escape from this town someday
はるか北の国に旅して　オーロラをこの目で見ることです
And travel to a faraway place and watch the auroras with these eyes
そこにあなたがニャンニャンニャン
To be with you nyan nyan nyan
居てくれたんなら素敵でしょう
What a wonderful thought that would be
だけどそれは叶わないらしい...
But it's just a dream that won't come true...
生き方はニャンニャンニャン
To change someone's life nyan nyan nyan
そう簡単には変えられないの
It is not that easy to do
それに私を飼っている　女の子を一人にできないわ
And the girl who is taking care of me cannot be by herself
話の途中よニャンニャンニャン
We're in the middle of talking, nyan nyan nyan
あらもう行っちゃうの?ねえちょっと!
Ah, are you leaving already? Wait a minute!
明日もここに来ていいのよ　待ってるから...
It's alright if you come back tomorrow...
これは可愛いお嬢さん
Oh, what do we have here, a cute lady
真っ白な毛がとても素敵ね
Your white fur is so very lovely
こんな月が綺麗な夜は　僕と一緒に遊びませんか
In this night with a beautiful moon out, will you go out and play with me?
あら正直ね、でもそんなやり方じゃ
What frankness, but with that kind of method
ココロ揺らがないわ
You cannot sway this heart of mine
私の夢はニャンニャンニャン
My dream is nyan nyan nyan
いつかはこの街を飛び出して
To escape from this town someday
はるか北の国に旅して　オーロラをこの目で見ることです
And travel to a faraway place and watch the auroras with these eyes
そこにあなたがニャンニャンニャン
To be with you nyan nyan nyan
居てくれたんなら素敵でしょう
What a wonderful thought that would be
だけどそれは叶わないらしい...
But it's just a dream that won't come true...
生き方はニャンニャンニャン
To live your life nyan nyan nyan
そう簡単には変えられないの
It is not that easy to change
それに私を飼っている　女の子を一人にできないわ
And the girl who is taking care of me cannot be by herself
話の途中よニャンニャンニャン
We're in the middle of talking, nyan nyan nyan
あらもう行っちゃうの?ねえちょっと!
Ah, are you leaving already? Wait a minute!
明日もここに来ていいのよ　待ってるから...
It's alright if you come back tomorrow...
はーい、というわけでるしあが歌ってくれましたー！
Hi there! So Rushia sang for us!
るしあ歌えなかったー！
Rushia couldn't sing it!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
歌えなかったね。
You couldn't sing it, huh?
そう、というわけで、えっと、るしとの曲は、えー、素晴らしきニャンセにしました。
Right, so for the song with Rushia, we chose 'Wonderful Nyanse'.
知ってたかなみんな？
Did you all know?
知ってた？
Did you know?
はい。
Yes.
ちょっとこれはね、船長のチョイスで、なんでこの曲にしたかというとね、
Now, this was the Captain's choice. As for why I chose this song...
やっぱり、船長の中でるしあってけっこう猫のイメージ、
Well, in the Captain's mind, Rushia kind of has a cat image,
おやー？おやー？
Oh? Oh?
おやー？猫なんだるしあわー！かわいいー！
Oh? Rushia is a cat! So cute!
ねこっぽいねって思ってて、で、そんな
I thought she was cat-like, and so,
ちょっと高飛車というか、なんか、かわれて、綺麗な猫ちゃんのるしあを、こう、口説きに行く、ぼく、みたいな見た目だったのね？
a bit arrogant... dressing up nicely, a pretty cat Rushia, and I go on to hit on her, like that.
見栄張ってたのね？
You were putting up a front, huh?
そう、口説きたかったのね。
Right, you wanted to hit on her.
だからちょっと今回はこの曲にいたしましたと。
That's why I decided on this song this time.
いやーちょっと。どうだったるしあ？この曲はね、そんなにマリンがるしあのことを考えてくれて曲なんだね。
Man, how was it, Rushia? This song... Marine thought so much about Rushia to pick it, you know.
そうだよるしあ、ニャンコるしあかわいかったなー！
That's right, Rushia. Nyan-cat Rushia was so cute!
かわいかった？やったー！
Cute? Yay!
うれしい！かわいいマリンだね。
I'm so happy! Such a cute Marine.
スパダリ具合も見れて、るしあよかった！
I got to see your big-daddy/cool side too, it was great!
いや、ネコのるしあ、もうずっとニャンニャンしてほしいな、るしあに。
Man, cat Rushia, I want you to keep Nyan-nyan-ing forever, Rushia.
ほんと？
Really?
うん、いくにゃーん、にゃーん、まりんにゃーん、にゃーん
Yup! Iku-nyan nyan, Marine-nyan nyan...
にゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃにゃあー！
Nyan nyan nyan nyan nyan nyan nyan nyan nyan nyan nyan nyan nyaaa!
まりーん！
Marine!
まりーん！まりんが、まりんが行き止まりじゃん！まりんまりん、いっ
Marine! Marine is... Marine, it's a dead end! Marine Marine, i...
ん、これはネクロマンサーしなきゃ。にゃんにゃんまりんいって帰れにゃーん！もんまりんにゃんにゃんにゃん！行って帰れにゃーん！まりんまりんまりーん！
Hm, this is a necromancer duty. Nyan-nyan Marine, go and come back nyan! Mon Marine nyan nyan nyan! Go and come back nyan! Marine Marine Marine!
にゃんにゃん！ネクロマンサーさーん！にゃーん！行く！
Nyan nyan! Necromancer-san! Nyan! Going!
るしあありがとう！るしあが可愛すぎるおかげで、行き戻れました。
Rushia, thank you! Thanks to Rushia being too cute, I made it back and forth.
いや、可愛い。可愛いニャンカプって、るしあしか勝たん！
Man, cute! Cute Nyan-couple, Rushia is the only one!
るしあんパワーだ！かたん！かたん！あー、かわいいよるしあ。
Rushian power! Katan! Katan! Ah, so cute, Rushia.
るしあ、幸せだなー。幸せだね、るしあ。
Rushia is so happy. We're happy, Rushia.
うん。るしあさーん。
Yeah. Rushia-san.
うん、今この時間がすごく幸せなんだよね。
Yeah, right now this time is so happy.
いや、わかるよ、船長もだよ。
Yeah, I know, the Captain too.
え、ほんと？いつもマリンって浮気ばっかりするけど、
Eh, really? Marine always cheats on me though,
いやいやいやいや！るしあは、今るしあしか見えとらん！
No no no no! Right now I only see Rushia!
るしあしか勝たん！
Rushia is the only one!
あ、もう本当にこれはもう何も言うことないわ。
Ah, really, at this point there's nothing else to say.
うん、そうだね。まりーん。
Yeah, that's right. Marine.
うん、今さ、この幸せな時間にさ、一緒に
Yeah, right now, in this happy time, together...
しの？
Die?
ちょっと待って、るしあ、まりん何逃げるの？待って待って！ちょっとちょっとそれ何？
Wait a minute, Rushia, Marine, why are you running? Wait wait! Wait, what is that?
るしあ、待って、逃がさないよ、ダメだよ！るしあ、やめて！だけでしょ！ダメダメ、なんで逃げるの、なんで逃げるの！？嘘つき！嘘つき！２人をも許さな
Rushia, wait, I won't let you escape, no way! Rushia, stop! That's it! No way, why are you running, why are you running!? Liar! Liar! I won't forgive the two...
こころ ぴょんぴょん 待ち？考える ふりして もう ちょっと 近づいちゃえ
Heart going pyon-pyon, waiting? Acting like you're thinking, getting just a bit closer
簡単 に は 教え ないっ
I won't tell you so easily!
こんなに 好き な こと は 内緒 な の
That I like you this much is a secret
ふわふわ どきどき 内緒 です よ
Fluffy and heart-pounding, it's a secret, you know?
はじめ が かんじん つーだ つーだ
The beginning is crucial, tsuunda tsuunda
ふわふわ どきどき 内緒 だって ば
Fluffy and heart-pounding, it's a secret, I said
いたずら 笑顔 で ぴょんぴょん
With a mischievous smile, pyon-pyon!
扉 開け た とたん 見知らぬ 世界 へ と
The moment I opened the door into an unfamiliar world,
(そんな の ない よ) ありえない
(No way!) That's impossible
それ が ありえる かも ミルク 色 の 異世界
Could it actually be possible? A milk-colored alternate dimension
(コーヒー カップ) 覗い たら
Peeking into the (coffee cup)
私 が 私 を 見つめ て まし た
I found myself staring right back at me
なんで ？ なんで ？ ふたり いる ？ (うそ ！)
Why? Why? Are there two of us? (No way!)
困り ます ね (きっと) おんなじ 趣味 (だから) 誰 を (見つめる の ？ 君 でしょ ！)
How troubling (surely) because we share the same tastes (so) Who are you (looking at? It's you!)
君 だけ 見 てる よ
I'm looking only at you
(これ は 夢 カップ の 夢 飲み ほし て おしまい ！) いつも ぴょんぴょん 可能 ！
(Is this a dream? A cup's dream? Drink it all up and finish!) Always pyon-pyon possible!
楽し さ 求め て もう ちょっと はじけ ちゃう
Seeking out fun, let's burst out just a little more
一緒 なら 素敵 だー い ！ 君 に 言わ せ たい から (言い なさいっ)
If we're together, it's wonderful! Because I want you to say it (Say it!)
こころ ぴょんぴょん 待ち？考える ふりして もう ちょっと 近づいちゃえ
Are you waiting, heart going pyon-pyon? Acting like you're thinking, getting just a bit closer
簡単 に は 教え ないっ
I won't tell you so easily!
こんなに 好き な こと は 内緒 な の
That I like you this much is a secret
ふわふわ どきどき 内緒 です よ
Fluffy and heart-pounding, it's a secret, you know?
はじめ が かんじん つーだ つーだ
The beginning is crucial, tsuunda tsuunda
ふわふわ どきどき 内緒 だって ば
Fluffy and heart-pounding, it's a secret, I said
いたずら 笑顔 で ぴょんぴょん
With a mischievous smile, pyon-pyon!
日常 の 中 に も 不思議 の 交差点
Even in daily life, an intersection of wonders
(それ なら ある ね) ありえる ん
(If so, that's right) It's possible
ありえない 角度 に 切り分け た ケーキ が
A cake sliced at an impossible angle
(さすがに ウサギ) 呼ん じゃ っ た よ
(The wandering rabbit) called out to me
私 も 私 と 驚き まし た
I was just as surprised as myself
なんで ？ なんで ？ しゃべる ウサ ？ (まじ ！)
Why? Why? A talking rabbit? (Seriously!)
困り まし た (熱い) お茶 を 飲ん で (そう だ) ついに (見つけ た よ 君 へ の) 君 と の 運命
How troubling (hot) drink some tea (that's right) At last (I found it, towards you) My destiny with you
胸 が らんらん 歌う ！ スキップ し ながら
My chest sings ran-ran! While skipping,
ににかん で 誘っ て よ (らんらん と)
acting shy, and inviting me (ran-ran to)
一緒 なら 無敵 だー い ！
If we're together, we're invincible!
本音 かくせ なく なる (本音 だっ)
I can't hide my true feelings anymore (It's my true feeling)
あした らんらん 希望 ？
Tomorrow, ran-ran, hope?
今 すぐ が いい な はにかん で 誘っ て よ
I want it right now, acting shy, and inviting me
最高ですか？
Is it the best?
最高です！
It's the best!
幸せですか？
Are you happy?
幸せです！
I'm happy!
最高ですか？
Is it the best?
最高です！
It's the best!
幸せですか？
Are you happy?
幸せです！
I'm happy!
お付き合いしちゃって 同棲とか始めちゃって
Started dating, started living together,
好き好き大好き困っちゃう 新郎新婦になりたーい！
Loving you so much! I wanna be the bride & groom!
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
High! High! High! High! High! High!
ぺこマリ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
PekoMari! High! High! High! High!
ぺこらとマリンはてぇてぇ
Pekora and Marine are so precious!
婚約指輪はどうするの？ 給料半年前ぐらい？
What about the engagement ring? Half a year's salary?
新居の間取りはどうするの？ 7LDDDKK
What about the house plan? 7 bedrooms, 3 living rooms
(え～)
(Ehh~)
世界一可愛くなるから 世界一かっこよくいてね？
I'll be the cutest in the world, so be the coolest!
愛してると毎日言って あと「大好き」も忘れずに！
Say "I love you" every day, don't forget "I love you"!
お父さんお母さん お許しください 結婚します ご祝儀！
Mom and dad, please give us your blessing, we're getting married!
もっともっともっと積んでいいぺこよー？ お願い！
Can you pile it up more and more, peko~? Please!
人生最高の日に 祝福を受ける二人 好き好き大好き困っちゃう 新郎新婦の入場
On the best day of our lives, receiving blessings, bride & groom entrance!
大好きな人 大切な人 力合わせて生きていきます ちゅ
The person I love most, precious person, we will live joining forces! Chu~
ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
High! High! High! High! High! High!
ぺこマリ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！ハイ！
PekoMari! High! High! High! High!
ぺこらとマリンはてぇてぇ
Pekora and Marine are so precious!
新婚旅行はどうしよう？ 沖縄で水着とか着たい？♡
Honeymoon? Wear a swimsuit in Okinawa? ♡
ホテルでは何を食べようか？ 私の手作り料理
What to eat at the hotel? My handmade cooking!
(なんだ!?)
(Why!?)
世界一可愛いお前と 生涯添い遂げると誓う 愛してると毎日言うよ
With you, the cutest, I vow a lifetime! I'll say I love you daily
dear, pretty pretty my sweetest rabbit.
おじいちゃんおばあちゃん 娘もついに 結婚します
Grandpa and grandma, our daughter is finally getting married!
子育ての秘訣？ そうね夫婦として当たり前のことを
Secret to raising children? Doing what's natural as a couple
当たり前にするだけなんだけれど… しいて言うなら 二人の愛！
naturally... if I had to say, our love!
人生最高の日に 祝福を受ける二人 好き好き大好き困っちゃう 新郎新婦の入場
On the best day of our lives, receiving blessings, bride & groom entrance!
大好きな人 大切な人 力合わせて生きていきます
The person I love most, precious person, we will live joining forces!
妄想乙
Delusional level: max!
人生最高の日に
On the best day of our lives
祝福を受ける二人
The two receiving blessings
好き好き大好き困っちゃう
Loving you so much, I'm in trouble
新郎新婦の入場
The entrance of the bride and groom
大好きな人 大切な人
The person I love most, precious person
力合わせて生きていきます
We will live life joining forces!
ぺこマリ最強！
PekoMari is the strongest!
最高ですか？
Is it the best?
最高です！
It's the best!
幸せですか？
Are you happy?
幸せです！
I'm happy!
はーい、というわけで！
Haai, so!
聴いていただきました！
Hope you enjoyed it!
いやぁね、飛びすぎたぺこらね
Man, Pekora jumped too much...
飛びすぎたぺこらね
Pekora jumped too much
息切れ半端じゃない
I'm completely out of breath
でもね、ぺこらがぴょんぴょん跳ねるぺこらが観れて
But seeing Pekora bouncing around was great
いやね、今回この曲「デイ・ドリーム・カフェ」っていうね
This song is called "Daydream Cafe"
ごちうさの曲なんだけども
It's a Gochiusa song, but...
これもうどうしてもうぺこらが歌ってて息切れ半端じゃない
Pekora singing it was so out of breath
どうしてもぺこらが歌ってるの聴きたくて
I wanted to hear Pekora sing it
一緒に歌っちゃいました
so we sang it together
いや嬉しかった！ぺこらとね、歌えたのもすごく嬉しかったぺこらだけど
I was so happy to sing with Pekora, but...
デイ・ドリーム・カフェ、うさぎぺこらだからさ
Daydream Cafe, since it's rabbit Pekora
うさぎぺこらから歌って歌ってって、実は動かしたぺこらなの
Pekora asked to sing it, actually
絶対ぺこらの声で聴きたいもん、船長も
Captain wanted to hear it in Pekora's voice too
聴けたもん今日！やったー！
And I heard it today! Yay!
ぺこらもね、そうだからぺこらも嬉しかったよ、めちゃ楽しかった
Pekora was super happy too, it was so fun!
いやもこれを気にね、デイ・ドリーム・カフェ覚えたと思うからさ
Remembering it from this, let's sing it again!
ぜひ歌ってね
Please sing it sometime!
あっ、ぺこーら！
Ah, Peko-ra!
それもあるんだけどさ
There's also that, but...
いや最近さ、ぺこまりのさ
Lately, PekoMari's...
ファンアートってなんかちょっと増えてない、ぺこら？
Fan art has increased a bit, hasn't it, Pekora?
いやあんまりさ、そんなに２人でコラボしてないぺこらだよね？
We haven't really collaborated just the two of us, right?
なんか急に冷たく冷たくなっちゃってどうしたの？
Why are you suddenly acting so cold?
冷たく冷たいけど今日ちょっと２メートル近くに売れないからちょっと距離あるけどぺこら！
We're spaced out today, but Peko-ra!
いやぺこ、お前もあったのぺこーらなのか？あんまりさ、そんなに２人きりのコラブって
Have we really not collaborated just the two of us much?
そんなにしてないぺこだけど、確かに。応えんだよ、なんか。
We haven't done it much, true. But response is...
なんか増えてるよね？
It's increasing, right?
え、そうそう！だからね、最近ね、なんかぺこらが船長を実は好きでとかね、
Lately, Pekora actually likes the captain...
船長がぺこらをナンパしたらぺこらがドキドキしててみたいなの、よく見るのね。
People say Pekora gets flustered when hit on by Captain.
そ、それを見て結果
Seeing that, the result was...
どうなったかと言いますと
What happened was...
もしや船長って、ぺこらちゃんとちゃんとお付き合いしてる？
Captain, are you properly dating Pekora?
だってだって誰にでも優しいぺこだからさ
Because Pekora is nice to everyone!
だって誰とでも付き合えれば付き合いたいじゃないか！
Anyone would want to date whoever they can!
あんたやめなさい！いろんな女にさ、手出しのまくるの、やめなさい、ぺこら！
Stop that! Stop hitting on all kinds of women, Pekora!
いやでもなんか、そのぺこらちょっと今日冷たいけどさ、でもさ
But Pekora is kind of cold today, but...
今日さ、にじまずちょっと上、宝鐘マリン100万人記念ライブ！
Today is Houshou Marine's 1 Million Subscriber Live!
いや、おめでとうぺこ！何回もおめでとうぺこらだね！
Congrats, Peko! Congrats many times over!
ちょっと100万人っていうさ、ちょっとお祝いというか権限というか、それを使って、
Using that 1 million milestone privilege...
ぺこらちゃん、今日は、でれでれぺこらちゃんに、なんて言いなさい！
Pekora-chan, today, say something sweet to dere-dere Pekora!
リバースカードオープン！
Reverse card open!
まさかのぺこらの100万人記念カードを発動！
Activating Pekora's 1 million milestone card!
これは様々言う権限をすべて無効にする！
This nullifies all authority to say various things!
皆の前で歌いたい歌を歌えちゃうね！
You can sing whatever song you want in front of everyone!
こんなどうでもいいことに使うな！ぺこら！よそうなんて何回も記念に来て
Don't use it on such pointless things, Pekora!
重ねた手はぎゅっと離さずに 行くよ 行こう
Holding our intertwined hands tightly, let's go forward!
夢見る空へ
To the sky of my dreams,
窓越しに見上げた とても小さな空
Looking out the window at the tiny sky,
ここで出会えたのは 数えきれない奇跡
Meeting you here is a countless miracle.
繰り返し踏み出した一歩が 切れ目をつないで
The steps we repeatedly took connected the gaps,
星のような笑顔導いた
And guided us to smiles like stars.
Day by day みんなの声が力になる
Day by day, everyone's voice becomes my strength.
Stage by stage ここでそれぞれ目ざすもの
Stage by stage, what each of us aims for here,
それぞれ描くもの それぞれ願った夢
What each draws, the dream each wished for.
重ねた手はぎゅっと離さずに
Holding our intertwined hands tightly without letting go,
一人一人違う色で描き出すトキメキ
Drawing excitement in each person's unique colors,
振り向くことなくまっすぐに
Rushing straight ahead without looking back.
行こう 夢見る空へ
Let's go to the sky of our dreams!
笑い合ったことや 尽きそうにない話題
Things we laughed about, endless topics,
思い出いっぱいなのに あっという間の日々
Even with so many memories, days pass in a blink.
上書きじゃなくて名前つけて保存
Instead of overwriting, saving with a name,
誰も全部大事で息ができる
Everything is precious to everyone, letting us breathe.
One for all みんなのためが力になる
One for all, for everyone's sake becomes strength.
All for one 共に賑やかすぎるくらい
All for one, just a bit too lively together,
笑顔が止まらない 甘い夢が膨らんでいく
Smiles don't stop, sweet dreams swell up.
重ねた今ぎゅっと噛み締めた
Savoring the present moment tightly,
一人一人違う声でたどりえは広がる 風を感じたらまっすぐに
Our destinations expand with unique voices; feeling the wind, straight ahead.
行こう 夢見る空へ
Let's go to the sky of our dreams!
憧れを手を伸ばし 掴み取ったその光が
Reaching out for our yearning, the light we grasped
いつの日か また誰かの憧れに変わる 繋げよう
Someday will turn into someone else's yearning, let's connect it.
重ねた手はぎゅっと離さずに
Holding our intertwined hands tightly without letting go,
一人一人違う色で描き出すトキメキ 出逢って すべてに出逢いありがとう
Drawing excitement in unique colors; meeting everyone, thank you for every encounter.
奇跡だって 私続け ずっと側にいるよ
Even if it's a miracle, I'll keep going, always by your side.
行こう 夢見る空へ
Let's go to the sky of our dreams!
find a reason to sing 君に逢いたい
find a reason to sing, I want to see you.
歌うこと教えてくれた君に
To you who taught me how to sing,
誰かがこぼすメロディーを 誰かが拾って
Someone's spilled melody is picked up by someone,
また誰かが運んでく
And carried by someone else.
名前も顔も分からない 繋がる奇跡が
A connecting miracle whose name and face are unknown
誰かを幸せにする
Makes someone happy.
君に逢いたい 歌うこと教えてくれた君に
I want to see you, you who taught me how to sing
今までは
Up until now,
find a reason to sing 君と歌えば
find a reason to sing, if I sing with you
時間を忘れ 夢中になれたんだ
I could forget time and lose myself in joy.
find a reason to sing たった一つの
find a reason to sing, the one and only
神様に与えられた贈り物
gift of talent given to me by God.
connecting, connecting with your song
connecting, connecting with your dream
connecting, connecting with your life
connecting with you
僕らは何度戦い
What have we fought with?
何に敗れて 何を失ってきたんだろう
What have we been beaten by? What have we lost?
名前も顔も分からない
Even without knowing each other's names or faces,
歪んだ言葉が 誰かの日常を奪う
distorted words snatch away someone's everyday life.
永遠に通じ合うことはないと思ってた 今までは
I used to think we could never understand each other, until now.
find a reason to sing 君と歌えば
find a reason to sing, if I sing with you,
独りじゃないと初めて感じたんだ
I felt for the first time that I wasn't alone.
ひとりじゃないと初めて感じたんだ
find a reason to sing いつか話そう
find a reason to sing, let's talk someday,
ちゃんと目を見て 初めましてを言うよ
look into each other's eyes and say "nice to meet you".
connecting, connecting with your song
connecting, connecting with your dream
connecting, connecting with your life
connecting with you
everything's too hard for me right now
その乾いた日常に夢をdownload
download a dream into that parched everyday life.
everything's a little crazy right now
その感情のままに投げつけろupload
just throw your feelings as is into an upload.
どうして人は巡り逢うのだろう
Why do people happen upon each other by chance?
こうして笑って 祝って 繋がって
Laughing, celebrating, and connecting like this,
そして次は 何が起きるのか
and then, what will happen next?
maybe nobody knows
誰かの叫ぶ声がする
I hear somebody's screaming cries,
行き場を無くした あの頃の僕のように
just like myself back then, having lost my place to go.
名前も顔も分からない
Even without knowing each other's names or faces,
君の優しさにどれだけ救われただろう
I wonder how many times I've been saved by your kindness.
画面越し 手を伸ばし 次は僕が誰かを繋げる番だ
Beyond the screen, I reach out my hand; next time, it's my turn to connect with someone.
find a reason to sing 僕と歌おう
find a reason to sing, come sing with me,
時間を忘れ 夢中になれるなら
if you can forget time and lose yourself in joy.
find a reason to sing それはきっとね
find a reason to sing, that must be it,
神様に与えられた贈り物
a gift of talent given to us by God.
find a reason to sing 君に逢いたい
find a reason to sing, I want to see you,
歌うこと教えてくれた君に
you who taught me how to sing.
find a reason to sing 一緒に歌おう
find a reason to sing, let's sing together,
何もないけど 君への贈り物
it may not be much, but to you, I send this gift.
connecting, connecting with your song
connecting, connecting with your dream
connecting, connecting with your life
connecting with you
connecting, connecting with your song
connecting, connecting with your dream
connecting, connecting with your life
connecting with you
はい、ということで！
Yes, and so!
3期生みんなでコネクティング歌いましたー！
All of Gen 3 sang "Connecting" together!
いやもうめちゃくちゃ久しぶりにね、こうみんなで揃って
Man, it's been so long since we all got together
いや、これ思い出の曲やから、うちらのね！
and this is such a memorable song for us!
そうだね、みんなでコネクティング歌ったの思い出すね！
That's right, it brings back memories of singing Connecting together!
ちょっとね、前回のトヨスで歌った時とはね、パートもがっつり変えて、シャウトとかもね、ちょっとペコラちゃんにやってもらいました！
We changed up the parts significantly from Toyosu, and Pekora-chan did the shouts!
どう、スカッとした？シャウト！
How was it? Did it feel cathartic? The shout!
いや、高かったけどぺこちゃんな
Man, it was high, but Pekora-chan
声高いからさ、二人とも！
both of your voices are high!
うん、めっちゃかっこよかったよ！
Yeah, it was super cool!
初号機つけてた、初号機！
You wore Unit 01, Unit 01!
でぺこらは可愛かった！
And Pekora was so cute!
初号機ね、ちょっと、ちょっと改造ぶっちゃしちゃった、初号機！
Unit 01, I modified it a bit, Unit 01!
いや、っていうことでせっかくね、5人揃ってアイドル衣装を着てるから、
Since the five of us are all gathered here
ちょっと、これはさ、記念にさ、ちょっとね、なんか
wearing idol outfits, I thought we could do...
撮影会とか少しだけしませんか？
a little photo session or something?
やろう、やろう！いいね！やろうやろう！
Let's do it! That sounds great!
じゃあね、ちょっと、ここは、うん、いつもだったらよくカメラマンがさ、いてさ、どんなポーズしてとかあるけど、
Normally there's a cameraman telling us what poses to do, but...
ちょっとそれぞれ我々がやってみたいポーズ、5人揃ったからにはやりたいみたいなポーズをやってみようかなと。
since the five of us are here, we wanted to try poses we came up with.
じゃあ船長から！
Let's start with Senchou!
おっ、船長ね。みんな揃ったらね、したかったの。
Ah, Senchou. What we've all been wanting to do together...
体育会系？本当？本当？
Athletic style? Really? Really?
みんな、体育会系のいじをみせつけるのよ、うちらの。
Everyone, show off our athletic spirit!
こうして、こうして。
Like this, like this.
すごい、すごい、すごい！なんだこれ！
Wow, amazing! What is this?!
きゃー！すごい！
Kyaa! Amazing!
待って、端っこがつらい、端っこが！
Wait, the ends are tough, the ends!
端っこがつらい、端っこがつらい！
The ends are so tough!
ごめん、なんか1人だけ楽しててすみませんでした。
Sorry, I kinda got off easy and had it easy all by myself.
あの今回ね、あの主演マリンだから真ん中なのね。
This time, since Marine is the star, she's in the middle.
皆さん、ありがとうございます！
Everyone, thank you so much!
じゃあはい！はい！
Alright, pick me! Pick me!
やっぱ、せんたってもんをやろうよ。せんたもの！
Let's do Sen-tai! Washing!
うん、ですの！レッド！
Yes, Desu! Red!
シルバー！テベレン！
Silver! Teberen!
レシ、悩んでるねレシ。レシ、どれの、ちょっと引こうか？
Reshia is hesitating. Reshia, which one should we draw back?
ホロライブ・ファンタジー！
Hololive Fantasy!
炎がドカーン！やってくれ！
Flames go boom! Do it!
どう？ちょっとこれみんな記念撮影してくれたかな？
How was that? Did everyone take a commemorative photo?
でもなんか逆にさ、このユニフォーム感が、おそろい感がさ、戦隊ものっぽくもあるよね。
Actually, this uniform feeling gives off a sentai vibe too.
確かに！
True!
え、そうだな。
Um, let's see.
え、なんかあれみんな知ってる？あの、みんなさ、頭を、あのなんだっけ、太ももに乗せて
Where everyone puts their heads on each other's thighs...
太ももに乗せてなんかみんなで、なんていうの？
And like, do it together, how do you say it?
あ、分かった！分かった！
Ah, I get it! I get it!
え、なんかさ、こうやってさ、え？あ、そうそうそう！
Like, doing it like this? Ah, exactly, exactly!
倒れていいのね？座っていいの？
So we can fall down? We can sit?
いや、こうやるんだよ。こうやるんだけど、ここね、頭で行くんでしょ？
No, you do it like this. You go head-first, right?
それで、頭をマリン、あのノエルの頭がマリンに行って、でマリンの頭が…
So Marine's head goes to Noel's, and Noel's...
絆があれだからね！
Because our bond is strong!
これは難しいよ！
This is so hard!
円になって、互いにあれよ、太ももに頭を乗せまっくて…
Form a circle and rest your heads on each other's thighs...
ペコラ！ねえ、本当にこれ…ペコラ、まだ早かったみたい、ペコラね。
Pekora! I guess it was still too early for this.
いま、でも、エンジン、円の形になったら、めちゃエンジン組んだようになったからね。
Because making a circle looked like we formed a real huddle.
いや、あとで最後に組もう、ちょっとその前に。
Let's do a huddle at the very end, right before we finish.
リシアは、なんかしてみたいやつある？
Rushia, do you have any pose you want to try?
5人でしてみたいこととか。
Something you want to do with all 5 of us.
じゃあ、お姉さんポーズしよう。
Then let's do an "older sister" pose.
いや別になんか、こう、ねえ、どうしようかな。
Well, not really, how should we do it?
親切にしてあげるからさ。
I'll treat you kindly, you know.
見えてますか？見えてますか？
Can you see me? Can you see me?
こんな感じで、ちょっと大人です。
Feeling like this, a bit adult-like.
ね、ちょっと、さらに、お、いいね、うふふ。
Right, wait, even more—oh, nice, hehe.
ペコラもっと出てきていいんだよ、お前に。
Pekora, you can come out more, you know, forward.
もっと、あ、そんな照れないで、はいはい、もっと前でいいんだよ。
More—ah, don't be so shy, yes yes, more forward is fine.
あれ？あれ？あなぺこちゃん？
Huh? Huh? Ana-Pekora?
あーいいじゃん決まった！いいんじゃない？
Ah, nice, it's settled! Isn't it good?
ちょっと、いいね。これで大人になったかな？
Wait, nice. Have I become an adult with this?
たぷたぷだ。触ってんじゃねえよ！
It's squishy. Don't go touching it!
さ、さ、鎖骨にまぎれて…ごめんね、胸の前で。
Re-, re-, hiding in the collarbone... sorry, in front of the chest.
よし。
Alright.
じゃあそんなところで。
Well, around there.
じゃあ最後にね、あの曲をちょっとみんなでやらないと終れないなと思っておりまして。
And finally, you know, I thought we couldn't end without doing that song with everyone.
じゃあみんな、準備はいいよね？ちょっとじゃあエンジン組んでさ。
So everyone, you're ready, right? Let's make a huddle.
それじゃあ行くぞ！
Alright, here we go!
組んで組んで！オッケーオッケー！
Huddle up, huddle up! Okay, okay!
なににしようかな？えっと、ホロライブファンタジー、うーん、おファンタジーで行こう。
What should we do? Um, Hololive Fantasy, hmm, let's go with "Oh Fantasy".
オッケー！いいのか？
Okay! Is that good?
楽しんだよな！せーので！
Enjoy it, right! On three, ready, go!
せーの、で！ホロライブファンタジー！おも、おも、おーファンタジー！
Ready, go! Hololive Fantasy! Omo, omo, oh Fantasy!
せーの、で！ホロライブファンタジー！うーん、おファンタジー！
Ready, go! Hololive Fantasy! Hmm, oh Fantasy!
何叫んでんだろ？
What was I shouting?
やめてやめてやめて！正気にも戻らないで！
Stop, stop, stop! Don't come back to your senses!
海賊ならYo-Ho! 踊るだけでYo-Ho!
If you're a pirate, Yo-Ho! Just dancing makes it Yo-Ho!
さあいま旗を掲げろ
Now, raise the flag high!
宝鐘海賊団！ (出航！)
Houshou Pirate Crew! (Set sail!)
Ahoy!! 我ら宝鐘海賊団☆ ホロライブファンタジー
Ahoy!! We are the Houshou Pirate Crew☆ Hololive Fantasy
踊るAhoy! 見るAhoy!
Dancing Ahoy! Watching Ahoy!
ホイホイAhoy! Ahoy! Ahoy! 全身全霊だ！
Hoi Hoi Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy! With all my heart and soul!
進め！三歩進んで大航海！貝よりダイビング！
Advance! Three steps forward, a grand voyage! Diving for seashells!
歌え！歌え！
Sing! Sing!
最高潮のテンション 波の音に乗せどんぶらこ
Peak tension riding on the sound of the waves, bobbing along.
海でガールズパーティお暇で
A girls' party at sea, having free time.
兄貴がハッピー！
Brother is happy!
空では遠くをく、ヒラヒラ
In the sky, looking far away, fluttering.
山奥ボロボロマイハウスで夢、海で
Deep in the mountains in a battered my house, dreaming at sea.
はあ、神様、いつかこのマリンを本物の海賊にしたいくだあ！
Haah, God, I want to make this Marine a real pirate someday!
声を上げて最終こうだ！ 我ら宝鐘海賊団！
Raise your voices for the final act! We are the Houshou Pirate Crew!
コンパス片手に旗を上げ、この海をジャックしちゃおう！
With compass in hand and flag raised, let's jack this ocean!
よっそろ、ついておいで！ともにYo-Ho! Yo-Ho! 叫ぼう！
Heave-ho, follow along! Together, Yo-Ho! Yo-Ho! Let's shout!
ああ、最高の日！
Ah, the best day!
ようこそ 我が船へ！
Welcome to our ship!
Ahoy! 踊るAhoy! 見るAhoy!
Ahoy! Dancing Ahoy! Watching Ahoy!
ホイホイAhoy! Ahoy! Ahoy!
Hoi Hoi Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy!
1, 2, 3, 3, 3!
熱く熱く語ろうよファッション 想いを解き放て
Let's passionately talk about fashion, release your feelings.
輝く輝くきらめくファッション 形から入るタイプです
Shining, sparkling fashion, the type who starts with the appearance.
発射の準備を前へ走れ！ 舵こい列車！
Ready for launch, run forward! Row the steering train!
すっぴんもテレるわ！キラキラ！
Even bare-faced is embarrassing! Sparkling!
ジンボリ汗もしたたる女だけど
A woman dripping with sweat, but
はあ、神様！船長は船長だとなんされちゃうのですね！
Haah, God! Captain is told she'll get banned!
奪われたら取り戻せ！それが宝鐘海賊団！
If it's taken, take it back! That's the Houshou Pirate Crew!
君たちとならたどり着ける伝説のエルドラド！
With you guys, we can reach the legendary El Dorado!
よっそろ楽しけりゃ歌いYo-Ho! Yo-Ho! 恥じない！
Heave-ho, if it's fun, sing Yo-Ho! Yo-Ho! Without shame!
ああこの景色 大切な仲間よ！
Ah, this scenery, my precious comrades!
宴だ宴だ騒げや騒げ！ 踊るはほーい、に見るあほい！
A banquet, a banquet, make noise! Dancing is Hoi, watching is Ahoy!
同じあほなら踊らにゃ損々！ 稼ぐは片手にいきますよ！
If you're a fool anyway, you'll lose out if you don't dance! Going with earnings in one hand!
それAhoy! Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy!
That's Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy! Ahoy!
宝鐘マリン！世界で一番かわいいよ！
Houshou Marine! The cutest in the world!
メスガキメスガキエロガキエロガキボンキュッボーン！
Brat, brat, lewd brat, lewd brat, bon-kyu-bon!
お嬢ちゃんパンツ何色？パンツはいりません！
Little girl, what color are your panties? No panties needed!
お宝、お宝、もっとい、もっとい！
Treasure, treasure, more, more!
なんでもストーン！なんでもストーン！
Anything stone! Anything stone!
船長なさったいいとこ見てみたい！
Captain, I want to see your cool side!
あはんあはんもっともっとうふふふもっともっとセクシービーム！もっともっと！
Ahan, ahan, more, more, uhehehe, more, more, sexy beam! More, more!
ほいっ！ よいしょ マッピング！
Hoi! Yoisho, mapping!
待った 待った 道中の 待った 待った 待った！
Wait, wait, along the way, wait, wait, wait!
際限ないすー！
Without limit!
もっと もっと もっと！
More, more, more!
萌え萌えきゅん！
Moe moe kyun!
もっと もっと もっと！
More, more, more!
出会って5秒で参しゅっこう！
Setting sail 5 seconds after meeting!
立てば地獄 座れば地獄 歩く姿はセンチティブ
Stand, it's hell; sit, it's hell; walking figures are sensitive.
夢を見なよ こんな舟で 後悔なんてさせない
Dream in a boat like this, I won't let you regret it.
君たちのおかげで わたしらは 船長になれるから
Thanks to you guys, we can become captains,
ミラクル船長キャノン うーてー！ ぶひー！
Miracle Captain Cannon, fire! Buhii!
声を上げて さあ出航だ 我ら宝鐘海賊団
Raise your voices, now set sail, we are the Houshou Pirates!
コンパス片手に旗を掲げ この海をジャックしちゃおう
Holding a compass in one hand, raising the flag, let's jack this sea!
両手を繋いで降りね ともにやっそー！ 叫ぼう
Hold hands and step down, let's shout "Yassou!" together!
ああ 最高の日
Ah, the best day!
ようこそ 我が舟へ
Welcome to our ship!
宝鐘の海賊団
The Houshou Pirates!
それでは行きますよ！ 連鎖っ！
Now then, here we go! Chain!
宝鐘マリン100万人記念グッズが出ますよ！
Houshou Marine's 1 million subscriber commemorative merch is coming out!
こういうのが欲しかったんでしょ？もうどすスケベ！
This is what you wanted, right? You super perverts!
なんといっても目玉はこちら！あかさあい先生描き下ろし抱き枕カバーです！
Above all, the main attraction is right here! An Akasa Ai-sensei original dakimakura cover!
君たちはどうせ汚すんだろうから予備も買っておいたほうがいいんじゃないですか？
You're going to get it dirty anyway, so wouldn't it be better to buy a spare?
表面からしてすでにデュエットにもこだわらず、裏面はさらに上を行くデュエットさで、
Even the front side doesn't hold back on duets, and the back side goes even further with duet-ness,
とてもじゃないけどYouTubeでは出せません！
so there's no way we can show it on YouTube!
是非概要欄のブースからイラストをご確…そして海賊といえばやはりみんな頭に巻き散らかしているバンダナ！
Please check the illustrations from the BOOTH link in the description... And speaking of pirates, of course, everyone has a bandana!
こちらはsaku39先生にデザインしていただきました！頭に巻いてもよし、弁当を包んでもよし、何にでも使えるバンダナです！
This was designed by saku39-sensei! Whether tied around your head or wrapping a bento, it's a bandana you can use for anything!
おしゃれっぽい柄なのでオタクなのがばれない…バンダナを巻いている時点でオタクといわれたらそれまでですがね！
It has a stylish pattern so you won't look like an otaku... though if you're wearing a bandana, you're basically called an otaku anyway!
そういえば先日販売開始したノエルの100万人記念グッズも3期生みんな映っていててぇてぇ感じです！3期生推しならこちらも手に入れておきたいのでは？要チェックです！
Speaking of which, Noel's 1 million subscriber commemorative merch released the other day also features all the 3rd gen members! If you're a 3rd gen fan, you'd want this too!
この夏ホロライブも宝鐘マリンもまだまだイベントやお知らせが待っています！どうかおっかけてください！君たちに感謝を込めて出港ー！
This summer, Hololive and Houshou Marine still have many events waiting! Please keep following us! With gratitude to you all, set sail!
本配信は終了いたしました。ご視聴いただきありがとうございました。
This stream has ended. Thank you for watching.